rockmelt.com 2012-06-28

# Privacy Policy | RockMelt

Effective 4/9/2012

RockMelt Privacy Policy

RockMelt, Inc. provides this Privacy Policy to inform you of our policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information we receive from you when you use the RockMelt Website (http://www.rockmelt.com), the RockMelt Browser, and various RockMelt Services. Together, we refer to the site, browser, and services as “ **RockMelt** ”). This Privacy Policy applies only to information that is provided to us through RockMelt. This Privacy Policy may be updated from time to time. We will notify you of any material changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on the RockMelt Web site. You are advised to consult this policy regularly for any changes.

**The Big Picture**  
Here are the basics:

  * We collect information about you and how you use RockMelt, and we use this information to make RockMelt better.
  * We protect your privacy and NEVER share personally-identifiable information with third parties without your permission.
  * To operate RockMelt, some anonymized data may be shared with third parties.
  * You can opt out of collection, either temporarily or permanently.

_Read on for details._

**PLEASE READ THIS CAREFULLY – IT’S NOT THE USUAL LEGAL MUMBO-JUMBO**  
RockMelt, Inc. is pleased to release this beta version of our product. The beta release provides an opportunity for you to try RockMelt earlier than the general public and provide valuable feedback that will help us make RockMelt better. Your direct feedback and comments are valuable, especially when combined with information automatically gathered about how you use RockMelt. To that end, RockMelt collects key information that helps us improve the product. Some of this information may be personally identifiable information about you (e.g., your login on Facebook, or Social Reading data if you have opted into the social reading service). We may also collect personally identifiable information about you in ways that don’t involve RockMelt products and services – for instance, if you send us an email with your phone number in it. We also collect information about your use of RockMelt and the configuration of your system. While this information is collected anonymously (no personally identifiable information is associated with it in our database), it may still be possible to associate the collected information with you (e.g., through heuristics or in combination with third-party data about you). However, it is our policy not to make such associations, and to make it difficult to determine such associations.

By agreeing to participate in this beta test, you are agreeing to allow RockMelt to collect these and other data points and transmit them to RockMelt’s servers. If you don’t want us to track this information, you have three options:

  1. For temporary periods during which you do not want information collected, open a browser window in Incognito Mode, which can be accessed from the RockMelt menu on Windows and from the File menu on Mac. We never track or collect usage data from a window while it is in Incognito Mode.
  2. Uncheck the “Help make RockMelt better” box under the RockMelt menu → Options / Preferences → Under the Hood → Privacy. Note that by doing so we will not be notified of browser crashes or other problems you experience and may therefore be unable to fix problems you encounter. We never track or collect additional usage data while the “Help make RockMelt better” box is unchecked. Note that unchecking this box does not stop collection of Social Reading data. If you do not want Social Reading data collected, go to the RockMelt menu → Options / Preferences → Edges → Social Reading, and click the “Turn OFF for all existing apps” button and uncheck the “ON for new apps” box.
  3. Remove RockMelt from your system and do not participate in the beta program.

Among the kinds of information we track, without limitation, are the following.

  * Which RockMelt features you use and how often (for instance, how often you use the friend edge, feed edge, share button, search feature, chat feature, etc.) 
  * The amount of time that RockMelt runs and the amount of time it is active 
  * RockMelt crashes and associated conditions around the time of the crash 
  * What you’ve selected for certain RockMelt preferences and options (for instance, whether or not you run RockMelt in full-screen mode, have one or more of your edges hidden, show the bookmark bar, and similar information) 
  * How often you use the omnibox / address bar to perform a search, whether you accept omnibox / address bar suggestions, and which ones (we do not store the search terms you enter or the suggestions you accept or are shown) 
  * Which other Internet browsers run on your system, and which browser is set as the default browser 
  * Your screen resolution, operating system version, CPU and memory configuration of your machine, and other configuration information 
  * The number of tabs you have open (but not the sites you have open in those tabs) 
  * If you have opted in to RockMelt’s Social Reading feature, we track the articles (URLs) you read on a set of white-listed websites 

If you open a window in “Incognito” mode, no data from that window will be collected or sent to RockMelt, and all data from that window including history and cache generated by activity in that window will be deleted as soon as you close that window.

Thank you for your participation in our beta test. Your contributions will help us make RockMelt a great product.

**Information Collection and Use**  
In this policy, when we say we “collect” information, we generally mean that the Browser keeps track of the information locally and then periodically uploads it to our Metrics Service. The Metrics Service stores the information persistently in a database for later use. When we say we “use” information, we generally mean that we store it, retrieve it, parse it, aggregate it, analyze it, report on it, combine it with information from other sources, and do similar transformations and analyses in pursuit of understanding how users in aggregate use RockMelt and how we can make RockMelt better.

Our primary goals in collecting information are to provide and improve our services, features, and content.

  * **Your Personal Information.** When you communicate with us or use RockMelt, we may collect personally identifiable information about you. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you (“ **Personal Information** ”). For instance, if you email us requesting support, you’ll provide us with your email address so we can respond to you. Personal Information can also include, but is not limited to, your name, phone number, IP address, or home address. (We might not ask you for all or any of these things, but you might provide them to us without our asking – for instance, in an email to us.) We use your Personal Information mainly to provide the Services and to respond to your requests for support. 
  * **Non-Identifying Information.** We also collect other information that you provide or that is provided to us about you when using RockMelt (e.g., without limitation, what search engine(s) you use, and your individual preferences) (“ **Non-Identifying Information** ”). We may also collect Non-Identifying Information about your age, gender, and city or zip code when you log into the browser. For instance, when you log in with your Facebook credentials, Facebook might tell us you’re a 28-year-old male from ZIP code 94105. This information comes from the data you’ve supplied in your Facebook profile and agreed to share with applications like RockMelt. This information on its own isn’t enough to identify you specifically. For our beta test, we also collect all the categories of information listed in the “Please Read This Carefully” section above. All this information is considered Non-Identifying Information. 
  * **How We Use Your Information.** We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) to provide you with and improve RockMelt, and to respond to your requests for support. 
  * **Aggregating Information.** We may aggregate the Non-Identifying Information we collect with similar information collected from other RockMelt Users to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of RockMelt, and to analyze and understand how RockMelt is used. We may also use information you provide without aggregating it to serve you specifically; for instance, to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions. 
  * **Demographic Profiling.** We might also use non-aggregated information for development or demographic profiling purposes, but any such use would not be personally identifiable. For instance, we might combine the information Facebook sends us about your age, gender and ZIP code with the data RockMelt sends us about your usage habits to find out more about which groups of people use specific Browser features. As an example, we might do this to get a sense of how many people aged 18-21 use the share feature, but not who those people actually are. 
  * **Newsletters and Marketing.** We also may use your Personal Information to contact you with RockMelt newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you, either generally or in your capacity as a participant in our beta program. If you decide at any time you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications. (See “ **Changing or Deleting Information** ” below.) 
  * **Log Data.** When you visit the RockMelt Web Sites (like www.rockmelt.com), whether you’re using RockMelt or as a non-registered user just visiting, our servers automatically record information your browser sends whenever you visit a website (“Log Data”). This is different from the information RockMelt will send us as part of the beta test as described in the “Please Read This Carefully” section at the top of this Policy; here, we’re talking about information that’s automatically collected by our web server in order to show you pages on the RockMelt Web Sites. This data is collected whether or not you use RockMelt, but only when you visit our website. This Log Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, the web page you were visiting before you came to our Sites, pages of our Sites that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Sites, access times and dates, and other statistics. We use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Sites and the Service and for the Sites’ technical administration, to increase our Sites’ functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor it to our visitors’ needs. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Sites meet the criteria required to process their requests.
  * **Third Parties.** RockMelt does not share personally-identifiable information about you with any third parties, except in those cases where you explicitly choose to do so, such as in RockMelt’s Social Reading feature. However, in order to operate certain features of the browser – such as, but not limited to, location awareness, comparative shopping, and content delivery networks – RockMelt may share anonymous, non-identifying information with third-party service providers, which they can only use in conjunction with the services provided to us. Furthermore, it is our policy to require these companies to enter into licensing agreements with RockMelt which explicitly prohibit them from publicly releasing personally-identifiable information. However, if you have directly shared data with those third party service providers in the past, they may potentially re-use or append your RockMelt data to their own customer database. This could also mean that your anonymous RockMelt data could become personally identifiable through the doing of such third party vendors. This Privacy Policy applies to RockMelt only, and RockMelt is not responsible for the privacy practices of any third party service provider who has collected your data, anonymized or personally identifiable, independently from RockMelt.

**Cookies**  
Like many websites, we may use “cookies” to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we may use persistent cookies to authorize you and ensure that only invited users are participating in the beta test. Second, we may use session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Sites, to better understand how you interact with the Sites, and to monitor aggregate usage by RockMelt Users and web traffic routing on the Sites. Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Sites and Service and then close your browser. We have no third-party advertisers on our Sites today, but we may in the future. These third parties may also place or read cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from any websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Sites or all functionality of the Services.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**  
_Compliance with Laws and Law Enforcement_.  
RockMelt cooperates with government and law enforcement officials and private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties that we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate to respond to claims and legal processes (including but not limited to subpoenas), to protect the property and rights of RockMelt or a third party, to protect the safety of the public or any person, or to prevent or stop activity we may consider to be, or to pose a risk of being, illegal, unethical or legally actionable.

_Business Transfers_  
RockMelt may sell, transfer or otherwise share some or all of its assets, including your Personal Information, in connection with a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of assets, or in the event of bankruptcy. RockMelt will notify you, by posting an updated Privacy Policy, before transferring your information to a new entity as part of a merger, acquisition, reorganization or sale of some or all of its assets if the new entity's processing of your information will materially differ from that set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Changing or Deleting Your Information**  
As the information we collect and store is non-identifiable and anonymous, it may be difficult (if not impossible) for us to locate and delete the data we’ve collected about you. If you would like us to delete any records associated with you in our system, please contact us and we will attempt to accommodate your request if we can locate the records, and if we do not have any legal obligation to retain the records. See below for privacy contact information.

**Security**  
RockMelt is very concerned with safeguarding your information. We employ administrative, physical and electronic measures designed to protect your information from unauthorized access.

We will make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your electronically stored “personal data” (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email, Facebook message, or conspicuous posting on this Site in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

**International Transfer**  
When allowed by law, your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country, or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide information to us, RockMelt may transfer Personal Information to the United States and process it there. Your explicit consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links to Other Sites**  
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy@rockmelt.com. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files to the extent possible. (See Changing or Deleting Your Information above.)

**Our Policy Toward Children**  
We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at privacy@rockmelt.com. If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

**Contacting Us**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@rockmelt.com](mailto:privacy@rockmelt.com) or at:

**Privacy Dept.**  
RockMelt, Inc.  
800 California Street, STE 300  
Mountain View, CA 94041
